David Mulyawan Oktavianus

Bandung, West Java, Indonesia | +62 851 5507 0838 | david.mulyawan97@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/david-mulyawan | github.com/davdmoo

Professional Summary

Software developer with a skillset in full-stack software development and almost 3 years of experience in developing applications for mobile, web, and desktop platforms. Managed to deliver a self-service bus ticketing project that processes up to 90,000 transactions monthly. Experienced in React, Flutter, Node.js, payment system integration using QRIS and EDC terminals, integrating with third party backend systems, and managing projects under minimum supervision.

Technical Skills

- Languages/Frameworks
 - 1. Typescript
 - 2. React
 - 3. Flutter
 - 4. Express
 - 5. React Native
- Database
 - 1. PostgreSQL
 - 2. MongoDB
 - 3. Firebase Cloud Firestore
 - 4. SQLite

Others

- 1. Next.js
- 2. Redux state management
- 3. Bloc state management
- 4. Linux

Experiences

Qios Teknologi Indonesia

Staff Programmer (Feb 2022 - present)

- Develop, maintain, and deploy a self-service bus ticketing platform using Flutter, Javascript, and Firebase to handle up to 90,000 transactions per month in Soekarno Hatta airport
- Develop, maintain, and deploy a self-service membership management platform using Flutter,
 Typescript, and Firebase for FTL gym
- Integrate QRIS payment with payment gateway and state bank
- Integrate payment using conventional EDC terminals
- Implement Firebase Cloud Messaging for payment notifications
- Integrate with existing third party backend systems
- Implement native Java code for hardware-related use cases using Flutter's platform channel
- Design and implement application error logging using Firestore SDK and Firebase Crashlytics
- Develop and maintain existing frontend codebases using Flutter for web and mobile apps
- Develop and maintain existing backend codebases using Typescript/Express
- Develop unit tests using Jest
- Collaborate and maintain good communication with cross-functional teams

Freelance

Full Stack Developer (2024 - present)

- Successfully delivered 1 project for a client in the retail industry
- Developed a Windows-based invoice management app using Flutter, Typescript, and MongoDB, focusing on invoicing and stock management
- Implemented features such as authentication, automated invoice generation, stock tracking, customer management, and monthly reporting
- Managed project timeline using GitHub Projects and successfully delivered within said timeline
- Created and managed monthly database backups
- Integrated Sentry for error tracking

Portfolios

1. Slinks (https://slinks.deno.dev/)

A simple link shortener web app to explore HTMX and Deno. Features include light/dark mode, QR code generation for links, and copying into clipboard.

Technologies used: Deno runtime, HTMX, SQLite, Hyperscript

2. Dictionary (https://dictionary-htmx.deno.dev/)

A web app designed for quick access to English word definitions, meanings, and pronunciations.

Technologies used: Deno runtime, HTMX, Javascript

3. rePath (https://github.com/davdmoo/repath-be)

Contributed as the backend lead during Hacktiv8 bootcamp's final project, developing a JSON API using Express and MongoDB. The project aimed to recreate the now-terminated Path social media platform.

Technologies used: Express, MongoDB, Javascript

Education

Hacktiv8 Full Stack Javascript Bootcamp (Sept 2021 - Feb 2022) (Grade 86)

- Learned programming from scratch using Javascript
- Gained hands-on experience in developing APIs, web and mobile applications, and software automated testing
- Developed skills in backend and frontend development using tools such as Express, Jest, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, React, and React Native

Padjadjaran University (2016 - 2020) (3.22 GPA)

Bachelor of Science in Chemistry